YI YU (BRUCE) LIU'S CV

PERSONAL DETAILS

Cell phone:(+27) 72 379 9000Email:yiyubruceliu@gmail.comCitizenship:Taiwan & South Africa

Location: South Africa

Driver's Licence: Light Vehicle (Code B)

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

March 2020 Designed and developed the UX methodology (with design thinking framework) and

Competitor Analysis methodology (with text analysis) that is practiced for every

future project at TypeDev Consulting.

28 Apr 2016 Runner up for Top Research (Field: **Text mining**).

4 May 2016 Graduated BCom Informatics with Distinction (**Cum Laude**).

Academic Colours at University of Pretoria

4 May 2016 Second runner up for Informatics at the final year of Bcom Informatics

Jan 2016 Top Winner of Investec national code-jam competition by outperforming all

candidates from UCT, WITS, and two other Universities.

The team leader of the following 3 Final Year Project awards:

Nov 2015 First Overall project Award with 86.5% Nov 2015 Best Documentation Award with 94%

Nov 2015 Most Innovative idea Award

Breaking the record for receiving more than 2 awards for this module since 2011.

Made it on "the Innovate" magazine in 2016 for the Project.

8 Sept 2015 Gaining an audience's respect by presenting at the "Transforming Thoughts into

Reality" conference at the UNISA Science Campus.

Joined by the CEO of mLab SA as well as mLab's Entrepreneur in Residence to present on the subject matter, being "Mobile, money and development: Connecting

the dots".

Mar 2014 First-year winner of the database project award (University of Pretoria). A friend,

Christopher Park and I achieved this by being the <u>FIRST</u> to successfully implement an electronic student <u>TimeTable software</u> into the *University of Pretoria* with the following

breakthroughs:

1. 5 000 downloads in the first year

2. 10 000 downloads in the second year

3. A 3-page article in "the Innovate" magazine in 2015

4. An article in the UP News post

Accomplished a program that generates 42 000 timetables in less than 10 seconds. It also provided a scale of flexibility for the students.

CAREER SUMMARY				
TypeDev Consulting				
Jan 2020 – Current	<u>Digital Strategist</u> - Designed and developed the UX methodology and Competitor Analysis methodology that is practiced for every future project. Stack: ReactJS, Flutter.			
Nov 2018 – Jan 2020	<u>UX / UI Developer</u> - Exceeding the client's expectation and gaining the complement "I paid nothing to get you productive" as well as "It's your fault for working so quickly". Stack: Jquery, Kendo UI & ASP.Net MVC			
TuksNovation				
Jun 2018 – Dec 2018	<u>Entrepreneurial Support Officer & Technology Strategist</u> - Accelerating multiple MVP development alongside CTO's of more than 5 startups. Assisting with Strategy, Technical capability, and UX.			
Jun 2018 – Dec 2018	<u>IT Consultant</u> - Leading the NGO business incubator to a successful start-up by establishing their IT sectors alongside the CEO and board of directors.			
University of Pretoria				
Jan 2018 – Dec 2019	<u>Junior Lecturer</u> - Served as second and third-year programming lecturer. Responsible for teaching industry-standard languages such as Angular 7 and Asp.Net MVC.			
Jan 2016 - Dec 2016	<u>Assistant Lecturer</u> - for the third year final year project. As a team, we took the initiative to empower students' through a networking event and teaching the importance thereof extended the systems and business analysis knowledge of the students for their year project by providing consultation for 15 industry-unique projects.			
Jan 2015 – Dec 2015	<u>Teaching Assistant</u> - for the second-year programming. Responsible for ASP.Net web application programming language.			
Discovery Vitality Life				
Jan 2017 - Dec 2017	<u>Junior Developer</u> - Developing in Java with Spring and Hibernate. Managing web services for the vitality system in the UK. Operating with the Linux servers.			
LiuPark (Pty) Ltd				
Dec 2015 – Jul 2016	<u>Co-Founder and Director</u> - As part of a team, I lead a web and systems development company to success by settling 4 client contracts within 5 months. This company facilitated and centralised our various website and systems development projects. However, the company is currently kept dormant until we feel that it is needed.			
Pretoria High School for Girls				
Jan 2013 – Apr 2013	<u>Chess Coach</u> : Innovating the coaching progress which resulted in a more interactive class of students. Gained consistent attendance from the girls because it was entertaining.			
Pattern Matched Technologies (Pty) Ltd				
6 - 10 Oct 2014	Job Shadowing - I shadowed the following and gained a full scope of their work procedure:			

Page 2 Yi-Yu (Bruce) Liu Last Updated: 2 May 2020

IT Support with Database Management
Business Analyst with System Analyst
IT Architecture
Quality Assurance with testing units

	EDUCATION
Sept 2019	MCom Informatics
	Master's Degree at University of Pretoria.
Nov 2016	BCom Hons in Informatics with Distinction (ABET Accredited).
	Bachelor's in Honours at University Of Pretoria.
	Research Topic Focus (Text Mining & Data Mining).
Nov 2015	BCom in Informatics with Distinction (2 nd Major: Business Management)
	Bachelor's Degree at University Of Pretoria.
Nov 2012	Grade 12/Matric at Pretoria Boys High School
	SKILLS

Expert/Specialist

- Problem Solving, Digital Strategy, and Critical Thinking
- Computer and Programming (C#, Delphi, HTML, Javascript, CSS, ASP.Net, Linq & Lambda, XML, JSON, Entity Framework), ReactJS, Angular 7, Flutter, Kendo UI, Jquery
- SQL and Database Management
- Microsoft Excel, PowerPoint, Word, Access, Visio, Project, Publisher
- Computer Hardware and Networks
- Communication, Public Speaking, Project management and Leadership
- UML (Entity Relational Modelling: ERD), IBM Rational Systems Architecture
- Logic and Algorithms
- Web design, User Interface Design, Web Development & Human-Computer Interface (HCI) Analysis, Bootstrap, UX Analysis
- Business Analysis, Systems Analysis, Software Modelling, Process Designs and Information Systems Development
- Search Engine Optimisation (SEO)
- Research

Extensive

- E-Commerce, Persona Design
- Data Mining, Text Mining and Business Intelligence
- Teaching, Explaining and Coaching

Solid

- Sales and Marketing
- Translation

Recreational

- Image and Video Editing

	LANGUAGES	
Current	Good Command in English	
	Well-spoken in Chinese Mandarin	
Previous	Afrikaans - Read, Write (Taken up till Matric)	
Translation	Chinese Mandarin to English; English to Chinese Mandarin	
Page 3	Yi-Yu (Bruce) Liu	Last Updated: 2 May 2020
bruceliu.info	yiyubruceliu@gmail.com	

ASSOCIATIONS

Golden Key Society (Member ID: 11954231) Jul 2014 - current

Dec 2013 - current Pretoria Boys High School Old Boys Association - Member

UP Consulting Society - Member April 2016 - current

WEBSITES

Websites designed and developed including Search Engine Optimisation:

autosense.co.za careerapptizer.co.za chylls.co.za bruceliu.info techtion.co.za katiso-engineering.co.za

PROJECTS

Feb 2015 - Mar 2016 As part of my INF 370-year project, myself and a group of students developed a fullscale mobile application and data mining service (known as the Career App.Tizer) for the Department of Education Innovation at the University of Pretoria. This app allows high school students to register and then fill in a career-guidance survey which will then give them the results relating to possible careers as well as Tuks courses for those careers. The results of the students will then be aggregated and analysed in the backend of the system to focus the university's efforts where needed.

The app was rolled out in early 2016 at careerapptizer.co.za

Reference: Dr. JC Lemmens - Juanclaude.Lemmens@up.ac.za

Jul 2013 - Current

My team members and I built a program called "Chylls TimeTable Assistant" which generates all possible timetables for the students automatically. Using this program, the students can choose from a variety of generated timetable options, rather than having to struggle with the conventional paper-based system. This program won us the "First-year winning informatics database project award for 2013" and has had ten thousand downloads.

The Facebook page: facebook.com/TimeTableAssistant

COMMUNITY

Mar 2014 – Apr 2014

taught the people in the Mamelodi Community, as a team, computer skills from knowing nothing about a computer through to enabling their ability to use the internet, make their own CV, operate their E-mails, Search for Jobs online, etc.

INTERESTS AND HOBBIES

I have a great interest in the psychological cognition of people which causes me to enjoy communicating with people at a deeper level other than just small talk.

Chess is interesting because it can stimulate the thinking in terms of the big picture as well as the small details of a situation at the same time.

Pokemon go has been a big hit since extroverts need extroverted activities.

Ukulele coming up soon.